The man. The legend. The truth.
Tyson is a documentary, drama film directed by James Toback.
Director James Toback takes an unflinching, uncompromising look at the life of
Mike Tyson--almost solely from the perspective of the man himself.
TYSON alternates between the controversial boxer addressing the camera and shots of
the champion's fights to create an arresting picture of the man.
Self, played by Mike Tyson.
Self - Trainer/Manager, played by Cus D'Amato.
Self - Promotor, played by Don King.
Self - Ex-Wife, played by Robin Givens.
Self, played by Mills Lane.
Self, played by Evander Holyfield.
Tyson is a 2008 documentary film about the life of former
undisputed heavyweight world champion boxer Mike Tyson.
It was directed by American filmmaker James Toback and produced by
Nicholas Jarecki, Bob Yari, and NBA player Carmelo Anthony.
The film was publicly screened for the first time at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival
and won the Regard Knockout Award at the Un Certain Regard event.
Tyson was released in a limited on April 24, 2009, then it expanded wide
on May 15, 2009, distributed by Sony Pictures Classics.
The film explores themes of sports, boxer,
biography, sports documentary, box ring.
The tone is emotional.